Are you one of those people who find the world of Western classical music a bit snobbish and inaccessible?
你是否觉得西方古典音乐世界有点自命不凡且难以接近？
The Proms – or the BBC Promenade Concerts to give the world's largest music festival its full name - might help you change your mind.
逍遥音乐节（The Proms），或者全称BBC逍遥音乐会——世界上最大的音乐节——可能会帮助你改变想法。
For eight weeks every summer, the Royal Albert Hall in London opens its doors to all-comers and puts on a music show that is varied and wide-ranging.
每年夏天的八周时间里，伦敦的皇家阿尔伯特音乐厅向所有人敞开大门，上演一场风格多样且内容广泛的音乐演出。
Some music lovers want to get as close as possible to the conductor.
一些音乐爱好者希望尽可能靠近指挥家。
They are happy to stand up to listen to orchestras and soloists playing symphonies, overtures and concertos by the world's top composers – all for just £5.
他们乐意站起来聆听管弦乐团和独奏家演奏世界顶级作曲家的交响曲、序曲和协奏曲——而这一切只需5英镑。
The festival has been going since 1895 and has always tried to be informal and relatively cheap.
这个音乐节自1895年以来，一直试图保持轻松友好和相对便宜的风格。
The Prommers – the classical music groupies who like to stand – typify this relaxed ethos.
逍遥音乐节的忠实观众——那些喜欢站着的古典音乐追星族——代表着这种轻松的精神特质。
Before performances, they shout out jokes and every time the lid of the piano is lifted they shout “heave” in unison.
在演出前，他们会喊出笑话，每次钢琴盖被抬起时，他们会齐声喊“嘿”。
One of the highlights of the Proms is the Last Night, which has a worldwide screening.
逍遥音乐节的亮点之一是在全球范围放映的“最后一夜”。
Popular classics are played while the Prommers wave flags and sing along to the catchy tunes.
演奏流行经典曲目的时候，逍遥音乐节的观众们会挥舞旗帜并跟着朗朗上口的曲调歌唱。
The Last Night is so popular with audiences that a ballot has to be held - several months in advance - so that everyone who wants a ticket has a chance of getting one.
“最后一夜”非常受观众欢迎，以至于必须提前几个月进行抽签，以便每个想要门票的人都有机会获得一张。
But it has been criticised by some for being too British and jingoistic.
但它也因过于英国化和带有沙文主义色彩而受到一些批评。
In recent years the Proms have grown so that they now include simultaneous screenings in other British cities, lunchtime concerts, talks, children's Proms, film and rock music, musicals, Indian classical music, and even tunes from the BBC series “Dr Who”.
近年来，逍遥音乐节不断发展，结果它现在包括在其他英国城市的同步放映、午间音乐会、讲座、儿童逍遥音乐会、电影和摇滚音乐、音乐剧、印度古典音乐，甚至BBC系列剧《神秘博士》的歌曲。
The expanding offer is proving popular with audiences old and new.
这种不断扩展的节目正受到新老观众的欢迎。
Perhaps classical music isn't quite so elitist, after all.
也许古典音乐根本没有那么精英主义。